<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="de.dim.bfr.feature"
      label="BFR Extensions"
      version="1.0.4.v20121009"
      provider-name="Stat-Up / Data in Motion / BfR">

   <description url="http://www.example.com/description">
      [Enter Feature Description here.]
   </description>

   <copyright url="http://www.example.com/copyright">
      [Enter Copyright Description here.]
   </copyright>

   <license>
      PMM-Lab © 2012, Federal Institute for Risk Assessment (BfR),
Germany
PMM-Lab is a set of KNIME-Nodes and KNIME workflows running within
the KNIME software plattform (http://www.knime.org.).
PMM-Lab © 2012, Federal Institute for Risk Assessment (BfR),
Germany
Contact: armin.weiser@bfr.bund.de or matthias.filter@bfr.bund.de
Developers and contributors to the PMM-Lab project are 
Jörgen Brandt (BfR)
Armin A. Weiser (BfR)
Matthias Filter (BfR)
Alexander Falenski (BfR)
Christian Thöns (BfR)
Annemarie Käsbohrer (BfR)
Bernd Appel (BfR)
PMM-Lab is a project under development. Contributions are welcome.
This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or
modify
it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published
by
the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License,
or
(at your option) any later version.
This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU General Public License for more details.
You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see &lt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&gt;.
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE AUTHOR AND CONTRIBUTORS
&quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES,
INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR OR CONTRIBUTORS
BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT
NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;
LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION)
HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN
CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE
OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
   </license>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.emf"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.persistence.jpa"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <requires>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.ui.forms" version="3.5.2" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.databinding" version="1.3.100" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.databinding.beans" version="1.2.0" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.databinding.observable" version="1.3.0" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.core.databinding.property" version="1.2.0" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
      <import plugin="org.eclipse.jface.databinding" version="1.3.1" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
   </requires>

   <plugin
         id="de.dim.bfr.jpa"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="de.dim.bfr.model"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="de.dim.bfr.ui"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="de.dim.bfr.knime"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

</feature>
