<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./PredictorView.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>Predictor View</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        View fitted models and predicted microbial concentrations
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>View fitted models as a graph and read out microbial concentrations according to defined time steps.</intro>
		
		<option name="Initial Concentration Parameters">Choose from the drop-down menu the parameter representing the initial microbial concentration for the given model formula.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Fitted models">Fitted primary or secondary models and parameters (e.g. from the Model Fitting node, the Fitted Model Reader node, the XLS Primary Model Reader node, the Model Creator node or the Predictor node)</inPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Secondary Models and Parameters"><br></br>
        <b>GRAPH</b><br></br>Visualizes secondary estimations and the associated model parameters.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>Mouse zoom:</b> To view a part of the graph in detail left click and simultaneously drag the mouse right and down. Another way is to use the zoom options in the context menu.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>Context Menu</b> (Right click in the graph):<br></br>
        <u>Properties:</u> Change font (type, size, color) and labels as well as the appearance of the graph.<br></br>
        <u>Copy:</u> Copies the graph to the clipboard enabling you to paste it in a graphical editor.<br></br>
        <u>Save as...:</u> Saves the graph as PNG (a bitmap image). Compared to the PNG image in the outport (which has a resolution of 640x480 pixels) this PNG is saved with the same size as on the screen.<br></br>
        <u>Save as...(SVG):</u> Saves the graph as SVG (a vector image). The file is saved with the same size as on the screen.<br></br>
        <u>Print:</u> Print the graph directly from Knime PMM-Lab.<br></br>
        <u>Zoom:</u> Zoom in and out or auto range the view for one or both axes.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>DISPLAY OPTIONS</b><br></br>
        <u>Draw Lines:</u> Connect data points with lines which helps to distinguish between different sets of data.<br></br> 
        <u>Show Legend:</u> Display the model ID and the data set ID together with symbol and color.<br></br>
        <u>Add Info in Legend:</u> Adds the formula to the legend. This option only available when the legend is displayed.<br></br>
        <u>Display Highlighted Row:</u> If checked, only the highlighted row in the table on the right is displayed. A comfortable way to select sets of data is to highlight a row and then navigate with the arrow keys (up/down). The space bar selects/unselects a set of data.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>RANGE</b><br></br>Set the minimum and maximum values for the x and y axes.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>PARAMETERS</b><br></br><u>X and Y:</u> The x-axis and y-axis show the bacterial concentration over time. The units can be changed.<br></br>
        <u>Y Transform:</u> Transforms the data on the Y axis (square root, ln, log10, basis e, basis 10). This is useful if a display of data other than the PMM-Lab default (log10) is wished for (e.g. as actual cell counts -> 10^).<br></br><br></br>
        <b>FILTER</b><br></br>Filter the model name or the status of the fitting to be displayed in the table below:<br></br> 
        <u>'OK'</u> means the model could be fitted to the parameter values.<br></br> 
        <u>'Coeff Out Of Limit' (yellow)</u> says that to fit the model to the parameter values the given minimum or maximum value of the parameters had to be extended. If this is not an option (e.g. because it is biologically not sensible) check 'Enforce Limits' in the Model Fitting node.<br></br>
		<u>'No Covariance Matrix' (yellow)</u> means that no errors could be calculated for the parameters. This also means that confidence intervals cannot be shown.<br></br> 
        <u>'Failed' (red)</u> means that the model could not be fitted to the parameter values.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>COLUMNS</b><br></br>Click on "Customize" to select the columns to be displayed, e.g. model name, quality criteria (RMS, AIC).<br></br><br></br>
        <b>TABLE</b><br></br>The empty table allows for the entry of time steps. The respective microbial concentrations are automatically calculated according to the model formula which is currently being displayed. These can be highlighted and copied (Ctrl+C), for example to paste them in a spreadsheet.<br></br>
		<u>Set equidistant time steps</u> Choose the number of time steps and the step size to easily generate time intervals of the same size.<br></br></view>        
    </views>
</knimeNode>
