<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./MicrobialDataSelection.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Data Selection</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Visualize values (e.g. microbial concentration) in a graph and select data for model estimation
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Visualize values (e.g. microbial concentration) over time (h) in a graph and select data for model estimation.</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Graph">Visualizes values (e.g. microbial concentrations) over time (h).<br></br><br></br>
        <b>Mouse zoom:</b><br></br>To view a part of the graph in detail left click and simultaneously drag the mouse right and down.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>Context Menu</b> (Right click in the graph):<br></br>
        <u>Save as...:</u> Saves the graph as PNG (a bitmap image) or as SVG (a vector image). Compared to the PNG image in the outport (which has a resolution of 640x480 pixels) this PNG is saved with the same size as on the screen.<br></br></option>
        
      	<option name="Display Options">
        <u>Draw Lines:</u> Connect data points with lines which helps to distinguish between different sets of data.<br></br> 
        <u>Show Legend:</u> Display the data set ID together with symbol and color.<br></br>
        <u>Export as SVG:</u> If this option is chosen, the outport will contain a SVG file and not a PNG file.<br></br>
        <u>Display Highlighted Row:</u> If checked, only the highlighted row in the table on the bottom is displayed. A comfortable way to select sets of data is to highlight a row and then navigate with the arrow keys (up/down). The space bar selects/unselects a set of data.<br></br>
        <u>Add Info in Legend:</u> Adds the name of the organism to the legend. This option is only available when the legend is displayed.</option>
        
        <option name="Range">Set the minimum and maximum values for the x and y axes.</option>
        
        <option name="Variables on Display">
		<u>X and Y:</u> Time is on the x-axis and value (e.g. bacterial concentrations) on the y-axis.<br></br>
		<u>X Unit:</u> Change the time unit to seconds (s), minutes (min), hours (h), days (d), weeks (wk), months (mo) or years (a).<br></br>
		<u>Y Unit:</u> For some diagnostic tests it is necessary to know the amount of bacteria in 25g. For this case and others the value unit can be changed.<br></br>
        <u>X and Y Transform:</u> Transforms the data on the X and Y axis (square root, ln, log10, basis e, basis 10). This is useful if a display of data other than the PMM-Lab default (log10) is wished for (e.g. as actual cell counts -> 10^).</option>
                
        <option name="Select">Either select all sets of data, unselect chosen data sets or invert the current selection.</option>
        
        <option name="Columns">Click on <u>'Customize'</u> to select the columns to be displayed in the table (e.g. temperature, pH. Click on <u>'Set Optimal Width'</u> to be able to see all of the text in each cell.</option>
        
        <option name="Table">The table shows the available sets of data, whether they are currently being displayed (selected), the color and shape of the symbol, the data set ID and the assay conditions temperature, pH and aw.</option>                
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data">Time series (e.g. microbial data) from spreadsheets (via ComBase Reader or XLS Data Reader) or from a database (via Data Reader)</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data table">Data table</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Data graph">Graph with selected data as PNG (default) or as SVG (see section 'Display Options')</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
