<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (C) 2012 Data In Motion
  
  This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  (at your option) any later version.
  
  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  GNU General Public License for more details.
  
  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./arrow_merge.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Table Array Merger</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Merges a single table with an array of data tables.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	The node merges a single table, either selected from a database or
	created by hand, with an array of data tables. Every table within an
	array needs a unique name. In case of tables that are selected from the
	preconfigured database, the table name will be identified
	automatically. For any other tables a name must be provided by hand. If
	the table's name at input port 1 equals a table's name at input port 0,
	the latter one will be substituted by the single table. The node also
	allows for initial creation of data table arrays: connecting a single
	table to the data table input port is sufficient. The node can be
	executed even if one of both input ports is empty.
	This node is most likely only used with the other BfR Nodes for prediction
	purposes. Its input ports will receive an existing table array
	generated by the <i>Load Related Data</i> node, and a user-defined table with
	values for time, temperature, pH and / or aw for prediction. The
	resulting table array can then be passed to e.g. a primary /secondary
	forecasting node. 

        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="table name">
        	The name of the data table that is to be merged.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="Input Port">Port takes a data table array.</inPort>
	    <inPort index="1" name="Input Port">Port takes a data table.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Output Port">Port holds the resulting data table array.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
