<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./FittedParameterView.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>Fitted Parameter View</name>
    
   <shortDescription>
        View parameters of fitted models and experimental conditions
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>View parameters of fitted models and experimental conditions. This is helpful for the selection of suitable parameters for the fitting of secondary models.</intro>
        
        <option name="Conditions to use"> First, add one or more experimental conditions (e.g. temperature, pH, aw, sodium concentration) to be able to estimate, which parameters might be suited best for the fitting of secondary models. Now select one of the parameters in the table. The first condition will be shown on the x-axis in the graph and the others can be defined in the section 'Other Variables'.</option>
        
        <option name="Graph">Visualizes estimated model parameters and microbial assay conditions.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>Mouse zoom:</b><br></br>To view a part of the graph in detail left click and simultaneously drag the mouse right and down. Another way is to use the zoom options in the context menu.<br></br><br></br>
        <b>Context Menu</b> (Right click in the graph):<br></br>
        <u>Properties:</u> Change font (type, size, color) and labels as well as the appearance of the graph.<br></br>
        <u>Copy:</u> Copies the graph to the clipboard enabling you to paste it in a graphical editor.<br></br>
        <u>Save as...:</u> Saves the graph as PNG (a bitmap image). Compared to the PNG image in the outport (which has a resolution of 640x480 pixels) this PNG is saved with the same size as on the screen.<br></br>
        <u>Save as...(SVG):</u> Saves the graph as SVG (a vector image).<br></br>
        <u>Print:</u> Print the graph directly from Knime PMM-Lab.<br></br>
        <u>Zoom:</u> Zoom in and out or use 'Auto range' to change the view for one or both axes.</option>
        
        <option name="Display Options">
        <u>Draw Lines:</u> Connect data points with lines which helps to distinguish between different sets of data.<br></br> 
        <u>Show Legend:</u> Display the model ID and the data set ID together with symbol and color.<br></br>
        <u>Export as SVG:</u> If this option is chosen, the outport will contain a SVG file and not a PNG file.<br></br>
        <u>Display Highlighted Row:</u> If checked, only the row currently highlighted in the table is displayed in the graph. This option is the default view in the Fitted Parameter View and cannot be changed.<br></br>
        <u>Add Info in Legend:</u> No additional information available.</option>
        
        <option name="Range">Set the minimum and maximum values for the x and y axes.</option>
        
        <option name="Variables on Display">
		<u>X:</u> If more than one experimental condition was added via the option menu the one to be displayed on the x-axis can be defined here.<br></br>
		<u>Y:</u> The parameter to be displayed on the y-axis is set in the table on the right and cannot be changed here.<br></br>
		<u>X Unit:</u> If the condition is 'temperature', the unit can be changed (°C, K or °F).<br></br>
		<u>Y Unit:</u> Units for parameters cannot be changed.<br></br>
        <u>X and Y Transform:</u> Transforms the data on the X and Y axis (square root, ln, log10, basis e, basis 10). This is useful if a display of data other than the PMM-Lab default (log10) is wished for (e.g. as actual cell counts -> 10^).<br></br>
        <u>Conditions:</u> Add experimental conditions to the variables in the display menu. Which condition is currently displayed can be changed in the 'Variables on Display' and 'Other Variables' sections.</option>
        
        <option name="Other Variables">Is more than one condition selected the other conditions can be configured here. Example: The inactivation of a bacterial agent was estimated for different temperatures, pH values and water activities. The change of the inactivation parameter k due to different temperature values i s displayed in the graph. Now choose from the 'Other Variables' for which pH and aw this change is displayed.</option>
        
        <option name="Columns">Click on <u>'Customize'</u> to select the columns to be displayed in the table (e.g. temperature, pH. Click on <u>'Set Optimal Width'</u> to be able to see all of the text in each cell.</option>
        
        <option name="Table">The table shows the parameter names which were previously estimated. In predictive microbial modelling, the extrapolation of test conditions is undesired and thus the minimum and maximum values for different experimental conditions are shown next to the parameters.</option>       
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Models">Primary and/or secondary models (e.g. from the Primary Model Selection node)</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Fitted Parameter Graph">Graph containing fitted parameters</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
