<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (C) 2012 Data In Motion
  
  This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  (at your option) any later version.
  
  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  GNU General Public License for more details.
  
  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Primary Forecasting</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
		Forecast bacterial concentration based on previously estimated primary models.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	This node uses primary models from the database to predict the
	bacterial concentration (log10 cfu per gram or per ml) at the given
	test conditions. The specified model, together with the estimated
	values, can take specified input variables and generate predictions,
	i.e. estimates for the response variables.
		</intro>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="In-Port name">
	A table array from the properly configured "LoadRelatedData" node,
	merged via the <i>Table Array Merger</i> with a table of input values created
	by the <i>Table Creator</i> node (which is part of the basic KNIME
	installation, not this BfR plugin). Place the Table Creator separately
	from the existing workflow. In the config dialog enter the desired
	points of time in one column of the empty table. Double click the
	column's heading and set the column type to "Double" instead of
	"String". Now connect the Table Creator's output and the
	<i>Load Related Data</i>'s output with the <i>Table Array Merger</i>'s input.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Out-Port name">
			A table array consisting of only one table, which contains the 
			user-specified times (input variables) as well as the predicted 
			values for each specified model. This table can be extracted with an 
			appended <i>Table Array Splitter</i> node.
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>